# MOHAMMAD HASHEMI

+989170133244

mhhashemi1379@gmail.com

github.com/Amahseyn

in linkedin.com/in/smhhashemi/

## SUMMARY

AI ENGINEER

I'm an Al Engineer with 3 years of experience and I spent most of my career doing Computer Vision projects. My preference is to enhance my skills in various fields (Machine learning and Reinforcement learning) and enjoy learning them. I am eager to solve difficult problems with simple solutions and want to be inspired by the tricks in real life.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Arooj Company**

Computer Vision Engineer • dec2021 - Present

## **Shrimp Head Cutter**

(jan2021\_jul2022)

- Design infrared LEDs and optimized camera parameters (ISO, shutter) to operate effectively in diverse conditions and capture better images to process.
- Process shrimp images and detect head shrimp at various angles using equalization and edge detection methods in OpenCV to work in real time with high accuracy.
- Implement in Raspberry Pi and test accuracy and time of processing

#### **Hand Vein Detection Device**

(jul2022\_dec2023)

- Designed and implemented a multi-condition arrangement of various near-infrared (NIR) lights.
- Configured an Infrared PiCamera system to visualize veins effectively.
- Process images using bandpass filters and OpenCv methods
- Preprocess images and create a dataset for training deep learning segmentation models (<u>Unet, Segnet, Yolo, MobileNet,...</u>) with pytorch/tensorflow framework and optimize models to work in real-time with Raspberry Pi.

## Freelance

2022 - Present

## **Persian Plate Recognition**

• Designed real-time plate detection model using TensorFlow/Keras and trained Persian character classification and create api with flask for Mobile App Development.

## **Tomato Leaf Disease Detection**

 Design and optimize deep-learning model based on CNN to detect Tomato Leaf Disease to work on embedded systems and mobile applications to work in real time.

## **Baby Cry Emotion Detection**

 Preprocessed baby crying voice, extracted features, designed a smaller deep-learning (CNN) model and enhanced the accuracy from 75% to 88%. Optimized the model for fast execution, ensuring efficient application in real-time scenarios.

### **Barcode Recognition**

Implement Image enhancer in OpenCV and image processing method in OpenCV to process low-quality barcode Images.

## EDUCATION

## **Bachelor of Telecommunications engineering**

Isfahan University of Technology • 2019-2023

## CERTIFICATIONS

**Neural Networks and Deep Learning** Coursera. • 2021

**Structuring Machine Learning Projects** 

Coursera. • 2021

**Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning** 

Coursera. • 2022

Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning, **Regularization and Optimization** 

Coursera. • 2021

**Convolutional Neural Networks** 

Coursera. • 2021

Sample-based Learning Methods

Coursera. • 2022

### SKILLS

- Computer Vision Algorithm
- Deep learning
- Python
- Raspberry Pi Development

- Machine Learning Algorithms
- MATLAB
- Time Series Forecasting
- API Models (Flask)
- C++

#### Familliar with:

- Reinforcement Learning Algorithms
- Docker
- Data Science Concepts